export const usHist1301Data = {
    "revel":{
        "Chapter 1":[
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did Europeans introduce to the Americas?",
              "Answer": "smallpox"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the country to the part of the Americas that it settled?",
              "Answer": "Spain – most of South America"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Historical narratives that focus exclusively on the actions of adventurers, missionaries, and soldiers in the Americas are most likely to emphasize the theme of __________.",
              "Answer": "material progress"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What were the main crops that formed the basis of agriculture in North America?",
              "Answer": "maize, beans, and squash"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What do archaeologists call the region crossed by the Paleo-Indians who migrated to North America 15,000–20,000 years ago?",
              "Answer": "Beringia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the peoples who lived along the Atlantic coast from present-day North Carolina to Maine share in common?",
              "Answer": "They all spoke an Algonquian dialect."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was practiced among the Eastern Woodland Cultures?",
              "Answer": "hunting and gathering"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In comparison to Europe, there were fewer __________ in the Americas before the European arrival.",
              "Answer": "communicable diseases"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which European country was already experimenting with unfree forms of labor on sugar plantations on Atlantic islands before the European colonization of the Americas?",
              "Answer": "Portugal"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did Native Americans most want to establish with Europeans?",
              "Answer": "trade relations"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects a result of the Columbian Exchange?",
              "Answer": "cultivation of the potato in Europe"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following accurately describes trade relations between African and European merchants during the fifteenth through seventeenth centuries?",
              "Answer": "Europeans had to observe African trade regulations."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following played a major role in the decimation of the Native American population in the sixteenth century?",
              "Answer": "disease"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Spanish monarchs sponsored Christopher Columbus’s “Enterprise of the Indies” because they wanted to __________.",
              "Answer": "gain an advantage over their rival, Portugal"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Where did Christopher Columbus believe that he had landed in 1492?",
              "Answer": "the “Indies”"
            },
            {
              "Question": "European monarchs sponsored exploratory voyages in the fifteenth and sixteenth centuries in the hopes of finding a water route to __________.",
              "Answer": "China"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The conquistadores were most influenced by the __________.",
              "Answer": "Reconquista"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following best reflects Spain’s view of its colonies in the Americas?",
              "Answer": "source of precious metals"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which group held the highest status in New Spain?",
              "Answer": "peninsulares"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the name of the system that granted a conquistador control over a Native American village and the labor of its inhabitants?",
              "Answer": "encomienda"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which country signed the Treaty of Tordesillas with Portugal in 1494?",
              "Answer": "Spain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects a synthesis of Indian and European cultures?",
              "Answer": "Virgin of Guadalupe"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The coureurs de bois partnered with Native Americans to obtain __________.",
              "Answer": "furs"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the sixteenth century, France’s rulers sponsored exploratory voyages to find a __________ passage to China by way of North America.",
              "Answer": "northwest"
            },
            {
              "Question": "All imports and exports in New France passed through __________.",
              "Answer": "Quebec"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to the English colonies, French colonies in the Americas focused more on __________.",
              "Answer": "trading"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who captained the ship that completed the first recorded transatlantic voyage sponsored by England?",
              "Answer": "John Cabot"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following constrained British colonial ambitions in the Americas?",
              "Answer": "the marriage of Henry VIII and Catherine of Aragon"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following contributed to the failure of the English colony at Roanoke?",
              "Answer": "the threat the Spanish Armada posed to England"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which country did England regard as its chief rival by the late 1500s?",
              "Answer": "Spain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which area was a major source of gold in the fifteenth century?",
              "Answer": "western Africa"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who established the basis for French claims to Canada?",
              "Answer": "Jacques Cartier"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the initial impetus behind European exploration in the late fifteenth and early sixteenth centuries?",
              "Answer": "European countries were looking for alternative trade routes by sea to Asia."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following facilitated early European exploration in the fifteenth century?",
              "Answer": "caravel"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 2":[
            {
              "Question": "Which European power claimed New York before the British acquired it?",
              "Answer": "the Dutch"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the colony to the religious group that settled it?",
              "Answer": "Massachusetts Bay - Puritans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to the colonists who settled New England, the colonists who settled in the Chesapeake were driven more by __________ motives.",
              "Answer": "economic"
            },
            {
              "Question": "A system of land distribution centered on __________ contributed to the growth of the servile labor force in Virginia in the seventeenth century.",
              "Answer": "headright"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the name of the representative assembly established in colonial Virginia?",
              "Answer": "House of Burgesses"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following terms refers to people from Europe who agreed to serve a master for a stated number of years in exchange for transportation to America?",
              "Answer": "indentured servants"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The charter of which colony sought to recreate the feudal system in North America?",
              "Answer": "Maryland"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was the site of a community of free blacks in seventeenth-century Virginia?",
              "Answer": "Pungoteague Creek"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following represents the Pilgrims' commitment to form a civil government in Plymouth Colony?",
              "Answer": "Mayflower Compact"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Puritans were products of the __________.",
              "Answer": "Protestant Reformation"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following statements accurately describes a major difference between the migrants to Massachusetts and the migrants to Virginia?",
              "Answer": "Most migrants to Massachusetts came in nuclear families, whereas migrants to Virginia were usually unmarried males."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which colony began as a settlement of men and women from the Massachusetts Bay Colony?",
              "Answer": "Connecticut"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people expressed religious ideas associated with antinomianism?",
              "Answer": "Anne Hutchinson"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following transferred New Netherland from Dutch to English control in 1664?",
              "Answer": "Articles of Capitulation"
            },
            {
              "Question": "During the early settlement of New Jersey, who was the only person who held the legal right to set up a colonial government?",
              "Answer": "James, the Duke of York"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Quakers prefer to be called?",
              "Answer": "Professors of the Light"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to Virginia and Massachusetts, Pennsylvania's population was more __________.",
              "Answer": "diverse"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Francis Daniel Pastorius's description of the ship that brought him to Pennsylvania as \"Noah's Ark\" highlights the colony's __________.",
              "Answer": "religious diversity"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was a feature found in both the Chesapeake and Southern colonies?",
              "Answer": "slave-based plantation system"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Before 1680, almost half the settlers in the Port Royal area of Carolina were from __________.",
              "Answer": "Barbados"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following emerged as the staple crop of the Carolinas in the late seventeenth century?",
              "Answer": "rice"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Most of the early settlers in the colony of Georgia were __________.",
              "Answer": "poor"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Of the colonies listed, which one likely had the most diverse, tolerant, and pacifist population?",
              "Answer": "Pennsylvania"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was Virginia's main export?",
              "Answer": "tobacco"
            },
            {
              "Question": "New England was the site of which event in the late seventeenth century?",
              "Answer": "Salem witchcraft trials"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 6":[
            {
              "Question": "Which state ratified the U.S. Constitution by 1788?",
              "Answer": "New Hampshire"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Federalists and the Anti-Federalists held opposing views on the __________.",
              "Answer": "U.S. Constitution"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The debate in 1788 over the opening of a new playhouse in Philadelphia became a forum for a discussion of the proper balance between __________.",
              "Answer": "public morality and private freedom"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which state was one of the first to sever ties between church and state after the American Revolution?",
              "Answer": "Virginia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Of the following states, which would have been the most opposed to the abolition of slavery?",
              "Answer": "Georgia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The work of which of the following people would substantiate Thomas Jefferson's statement \"that nature has given to our black brethren, talents equal to those of the other colors of men\"?",
              "Answer": "Benjamin Banneker"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the perspective of the leaders of the American republic on the question of women in politics?",
              "Answer": "The appointment of a woman to office is an innovation for which the public is not prepared, nor am I."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Most of the state constitutions that were written after the American Revolution had provisions that protected __________.",
              "Answer": "natural rights"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Under the Articles of Confederation, the congress had no authority to __________.",
              "Answer": "directly impose and collect taxes"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Of the following states, which initially stood to gain the most from the unsurveyed territory west of the Appalachians?",
              "Answer": "Virginia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which state was the first to cede its holdings north of the Ohio River to the Confederation?",
              "Answer": "Virginia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the late eighteenth century, the Continental Congress was primarily concerned with bringing order to settlement in __________.",
              "Answer": "the Northwest Territory"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the mid-1780s, many learned Americans who emphasized the sovereignty of the states were influenced by the writings of __________.",
              "Answer": "Baron de Montesquieu"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who led impoverished Massachusetts farmers in a 1786 uprising?",
              "Answer": "Daniel Shays"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following proposed a national legislature of two houses, one elected directly by the people, the other chosen by the first house from nominations made by the state assemblies?",
              "Answer": "Virginia Plan"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The three-fifths rule was a constitutional provision that addressed the issue of representation in __________.",
              "Answer": "the lower house of Congress"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would advocates of the doctrine of originalism support?",
              "Answer": "limiting federal authority over the states"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Federalists support?",
              "Answer": "a strong national government"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Among the following people, who was the most vocal critic of the proposed Constitution during the ratification debates?",
              "Answer": "Patrick Henry"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who drafted what would be adopted as the Bill of Rights?",
              "Answer": "James Madison"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who drafted most of the Constitution?",
              "Answer": "James Madison"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the person to the state that he represented at the Constitutional Convention?",
              "Answer": "Elbridge Gerry - Massachusetts"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was an argument made in support of a ban on importing slaves?",
              "Answer": "Slavery discouraged arts and manufactures."
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 7":[
            {
              "Question": "At the first meeting of the U.S. Senate in 1789, John Adams raised the question of how the president would be __________.",
              "Answer": "addressed"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people was the most vocal critic of the policies of Alexander Hamilton?",
              "Answer": "Thomas Jefferson"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the years following the American Revolution, a Republican would most likely support policies that promoted __________.",
              "Answer": "agriculture"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Judiciary Act of 1789 do?",
              "Answer": "established a Supreme Court"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following executive departments was created during the presidency of George Washington?",
              "Answer": "Treasury"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to Alexander Hamilton, Thomas Jefferson believed that a country’s fundamental economic strength stemmed from its __________.",
              "Answer": "agricultural productivity"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Alexander Hamilton believed that the United States should follow the economic models of which country?",
              "Answer": "Britain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The debt assumption portion of Alexander Hamilton’s recommendations in his Report on the Public Credit would benefit states that __________.",
              "Answer": "did not have their finances in order"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did Alexander Hamilton support?",
              "Answer": "limiting states’ ability to shape national economic policy"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Powers not explicitly listed in the Constitution but that are necessary for the government to do its job are referred to as __________ powers.",
              "Answer": "implied"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of Alexander Hamilton’s proposals did Congress reject?",
              "Answer": "impose protective tariffs"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would Jeffersonian Republicans support?",
              "Answer": "strict interpretation of the Constitution"
            },
            {
              "Question": "How did Alexander Hamilton propose the United States react to Britain’s treatment of the United States in the 1790s?",
              "Answer": "appease Britain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did Britain agree to do in Jay’s Treaty?",
              "Answer": "relinquish its frontier posts on U.S. territory"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was an outcome of Pinckney’s Treaty?",
              "Answer": "opening of the Mississippi to American commerce"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was the largest and most successful slave revolt in modern history?",
              "Answer": "Haitian Revolution"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who personally led troops to put down the Whiskey Rebellion?",
              "Answer": "George Washington"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Whiskey Rebellion widened the political divide between __________.",
              "Answer": "Federalists and Republicans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In his Farewell Address, George Washington advised that the United States should __________.",
              "Answer": "avoid forming permanent alliances with distant countries"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The XYZ Affair increased tensions between the United States and __________.",
              "Answer": "France"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Alien and Sedition Acts were aimed primarily at __________.",
              "Answer": "Jeffersonian Republicans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Whose perspective is presented in the Kentucky and Virginia Resolutions?",
              "Answer": "Republicans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the improvement of relations between the United States and France during the Adams administration?",
              "Answer": "Convention of Mortefontaine"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following accurately describes the newspaper industry in the 1790s?",
              "Answer": "The press took partisan positions."
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the late eighteenth century, which country joined Austria, Prussia, Sardinia, and the United Netherlands to fight against France",
              "Answer": "Great Britain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which treaty ended the Northwest Indian War?",
              "Answer": "Treaty of Greenville"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following resulted in a decisive defeat for American Indians?",
              "Answer": "Battle of Fallen Timbers"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What role does the press play in politics, and how important is this role?",
              "Answer": "SHARED WRITING"
            },
            {
              "Question": "",
              "Answer": ""
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 8":[
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following directly pitted the United States against Britain?",
              "Answer": "War of 1812"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did Thomas Jefferson do during his first term as president?",
              "Answer": "reduced military spending"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did critics of Jeffersonian republicanism argue was evidence of Jeffersonian hypocrisy?",
              "Answer": "Jeffersonians spoke about freedom and equality, but many of them owned slaves."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which river was the main commercial link for westerners in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Mississippi"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following statements reflects a belief that informed Thomas Jefferson’s Indian policy?",
              "Answer": "“The same world will scarcely do for them and us.”"
            },
            {
              "Question": "During the early 1800s, most of the American population worked in __________.",
              "Answer": "agriculture"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which innovation paved the way for the opening of new markets for American manufacturers during the 1800s?",
              "Answer": "steamship"
            },
            {
              "Question": "How did Thomas Jefferson pay off the debt inherited from the Adams administration?",
              "Answer": "cutting military expenditures"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which question made Thomas Jefferson hesitate before purchasing the Louisiana Territory?",
              "Answer": "Was the purchase constitutional?"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Thomas Jefferson commissioned what became known as the Lewis and Clark Expedition to determine whether the __________ River “may offer the most direct & practicable water communication across this continent for the purposes of commerce.”",
              "Answer": "Missouri"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The success of the Lewis and Clark Expedition owed much to the assistance provided by __________.",
              "Answer": "Sacagawea"
            },
            {
              "Question": "John Marshall’s ruling in Marbury v. Madison was significant because it __________.",
              "Answer": "established the principle of judicial review"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Marbury v. Madison pitted the Supreme Court against the __________.",
              "Answer": "Jefferson administration"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was Aaron Burr accused of in a court of law in 1807?",
              "Answer": "treason"
            },
            {
              "Question": "On January 1, 1808, a congressional law went into effect that __________.",
              "Answer": "banned the importation of slaves"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did the British government declare illegal in 1805?",
              "Answer": "“broken voyages”"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects France’s response to Britain’s “paper blockades”?",
              "Answer": "Continental System"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Tecumseh sought British military assistance against the Americans after the Battle of __________.",
              "Answer": "Tippecanoe"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Congressional War Hawks hoped that the War of 1812 would result in the annexation of __________.",
              "Answer": "Canada"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following battles was an American victory in the War of 1812?",
              "Answer": "Thames River"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Hartford Convention reflected the interests of which region?",
              "Answer": "New England"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Battle of New Orleans was significant because it __________.",
              "Answer": "secured the Mississippi River as a trade route for American settlers in the West"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following were part of Lewis and Clark’s traveling party?",
              "Answer": "American soldiers"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the territory to the country that claimed it in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Florida – Spain"
            },
            {
              "Question": "An important purpose of the Lewis and Clark Expedition was to __________.",
              "Answer": "study the waterways, natural resources, and native inhabitants of the Louisiana Territory"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 9":[
            {
              "Question": "Most of the new land that became available for white settlement after the War of 1812 was either acquired by treaty or taken from __________.",
              "Answer": "Native Americans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following helped to create a better-connected domestic American marketplace?",
              "Answer": "canals"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people would have most agreed with this description of the United States?: “Their citizens individually have been happy and the nation prosperous.”",
              "Answer": "Marquis de Lafayette"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following led to the U.S. annexation of Florida?",
              "Answer": "Adams–Onís Treaty"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What fueled expansion to the far west in the 1820s?",
              "Answer": "the fur trade"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which country had territorial claims in the Pacific Northwest in the early 1800s?",
              "Answer": "Russia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was part of the “Five Civilized Tribes”?",
              "Answer": "Creek"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to the Cherokee, the Seminole __________.",
              "Answer": "resisted white settlers"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The flatboat trade followed the path of the __________.",
              "Answer": "Ohio–Mississippi system"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the region to its major cash crop?",
              "Answer": "Deep South – cotton"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the main cash crop of the North?",
              "Answer": "wheat"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was a feature found in both the putting-out system of manufacturing and the factory production of textiles?",
              "Answer": "the predominance of female workers"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Under the Missouri Compromise, Missouri was admitted to the Union as a slave state and __________ was admitted as a free state.",
              "Answer": "Maine"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who dominated the Supreme Court in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "John Marshall"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following set forth the doctrine of “implied powers”?",
              "Answer": "McCulloch v. Maryland"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the spirit of the Monroe Doctrine?",
              "Answer": "U.S. recognition of the new states in Latin America"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects an assumption of the Monroe Doctrine?",
              "Answer": "The United States has a right to dominate politics in the Americas."
            },
            {
              "Question": "In 1820, most Americans in every state worked in __________.",
              "Answer": "agriculture"
            },
            {
              "Question": "From 1790 to 1830, which state consistently had the highest percentage of the population that was enslaved?",
              "Answer": "South Carolina"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Manufacturing was the strongest in which region of the United States in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Northeast"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 10":[
            {
              "Question": "The leaders of which state argued that they could nullify federal laws?",
              "Answer": "South Carolina"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following groups of people benefited the most from Andrew Jackson’s policies?",
              "Answer": "white men"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following symbolized the democratic spirit of the Jacksonian era?",
              "Answer": "hotels"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who would most likely have agreed with this statement?: “Paint pictures that will take with the public—never paint for the few but the many.”",
              "Answer": "George Caleb Bingham"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the person to the field to which she or he contributed?",
              "Answer": "Henry Wadsworth Longfellow – poetry"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The acceptance of the idea of __________ in the 1820s and 1830s reflected the emergence of a two-party system.",
              "Answer": "a loyal opposition"
            },
            {
              "Question": "By the 1820s, who had the right to vote in national elections in most states?",
              "Answer": "white men"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would an entrepreneur in the early nineteenth century most likely have supported?",
              "Answer": "state charters that granted privileges to banks"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which election was decided in the House of Representatives?",
              "Answer": 1824
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which group would be the most opposed to the Tariff of Abominations?",
              "Answer": "free traders in the South"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The treatment of __________ triggered a wave of resignations in Andrew Jackson’s cabinet in 1831.",
              "Answer": "Peggy Eaton"
            },
            {
              "Question": "When it came to Indian affairs, Andrew Jackson was a strong supporter of __________.",
              "Answer": "states’ rights"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following sparked the nullification crisis during Jackson’s presidency?",
              "Answer": "South Carolina’s refusal to be subject to a federal tariff"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who supported the rechartering of the Second Bank of the United States?",
              "Answer": "Nicholas Biddle"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In an effort to eliminate the Bank of the United States, what action did Andrew Jackson order?",
              "Answer": "removal of federal deposits from the bank"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Panic of 1837 occurred during the presidency of __________.",
              "Answer": "Martin Van Buren"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to the American political system, many European countries today have __________.",
              "Answer": "more than two parties"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Immigrants, Catholics, freethinkers, and backwoods farmers generally supported the __________.",
              "Answer": "Democrats"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the middle of the nineteenth century, a Democrat would most likely have agreed with which statement?",
              "Answer": "A laissez-faire economic policy allows for greater personal liberty."
            },
            {
              "Question": "America’s second-party system came of age in the election of __________.",
              "Answer": 1840
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the 1830s, which of the following defended Native Americans’ legal claims to their land?",
              "Answer": "the Supreme Court"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the nineteenth century, the U.S. government forced Indians living in the southeastern states to relocate to lands __________ of the Mississippi River.",
              "Answer": "west"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The territory of which Indian tribe stretched across parts of Alabama and Georgia?",
              "Answer": "Cherokee"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who would have most likely opposed the Indian Removal Act?",
              "Answer": "Ralph Waldo Emerson"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Explaining your reasons and considering opposing arguments, either agree or disagree with the following statement: \"A two-party system better achieves democratic ideals than a multi-party system.",
              "Answer": "Shared Writing"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 11":[
            {
              "Question": "Approximately how many slaves did the average slaveholder own?",
              "Answer": 10
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following prompted legislation limiting the movements of blacks in the South?",
              "Answer": "Nat Turner’s Rebellion"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following groups of people would have been the most opposed to Nat Turner’s cause?",
              "Answer": "slaveholders"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The “task system” was used in the cultivation of which of the following crops?",
              "Answer": "rice"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was generally true of large plantations with relatively stable slave populations?",
              "Answer": "Most slave children lived in two-parent households."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who mobilized a large band of slaves to march on Richmond, Virginia, in 1800?",
              "Answer": "Gabriel Prosser"
            },
            {
              "Question": "After 1830, slaveholders began to defend slavery as a __________.",
              "Answer": "positive good"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the relationship between law and race in the antebellum era?",
              "Answer": "It was a crime for a black person to be insolent to a white person."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following states was part of Cotton Kingdom?",
              "Answer": "Georgia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following conclusions did white slaveholders draw from Thomas Reade Cobb’s assertion that “a state of bondage, so far from doing violence to the law of [the African’s] nature, develops and perfects it”?",
              "Answer": "Slavery was good for African Americans."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following is true of yeoman farmers in the antebellum South?",
              "Answer": "They owned land they worked themselves."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Yeoman farmers in the antebellum South would agree with which of the following statements?",
              "Answer": "Whites represent the master race."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did defenders of slavery cite to support their position?",
              "Answer": "the Bible"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the nineteenth century, the economy of which of the following states shifted from tobacco cultivation to the internal slave trade?",
              "Answer": "Virginia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following were the first areas to produce cotton on a large scale?",
              "Answer": "Georgia and South Carolina"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following highlights the role of slavery in the wider economy in the nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Loans secured by mortgages used slaves as collateral."
            },
            {
              "Question": "In 1807, Congress passed a law that prohibited the __________.",
              "Answer": "importation of slaves"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Slavery was the basis of the economy of which of the following states in the antebellum era?",
              "Answer": "Louisiana"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following explains why the states with the highest percentage of farms and plantations that were 500 acres or more in 1860 were concentrated in the southeastern part of the United States?",
              "Answer": "The economy of the South was centered on the cultivation of labor-intensive crops that required large tracts of land and depended on slave labor."
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 12":[
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following became a target of attack in the movements of the first half of the nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "alchohol"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people was associated with the religious revivals that swept the northern states in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Charles G. Finney"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following offers the best explanation for why millions of African Americans converted to Christianity in the first half of the nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "The evangelicals preached the belief that everyone is equal in heaven."
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Second Great Awakening refers to a wave of __________.",
              "Answer": "religious revivals"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What kind of appeals did Charles Finney use to attract converts to his brand of evangelical Christianity?",
              "Answer": "emotional"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to the Great Awakening of the early nineteenth century, contemporary evangelical reformers __________.",
              "Answer": "hold more conservative views on cultural change"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the goal of the temperance movement?",
              "Answer": "reduce alcohol consumption"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was part of the benevolent empire in the early nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "American Temperance Society"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The evangelical movement strengthened women's role as __________.",
              "Answer": "moral guardians"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The idea of \"sorority\" was most relevant to the lives of __________.",
              "Answer": "middle-class women"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In which part of the country was public education the most developed before 1820?",
              "Answer": "New England"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who played the most important role in promoting educational reform?",
              "Answer": "Horace Mann"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following best reflected ideas associated with the \"Protestant ethic\"?",
              "Answer": "McGuffey's Eclectic Readers"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who would most agree with Reverend Nathaniel Paul's exhortation to African Americans to \"enter the field with a fixed determination to live and die in the holy cause\" of abolition of slavery?",
              "Answer": "David Walker"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who published the abolitionist newspaper, the Liberator?",
              "Answer": "William Lloyd Garrison"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Whose murder in 1837 discouraged abolitionists from spreading their message to the South?",
              "Answer": "Elijah Lovejoy"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was an expression of the Negro Convention movement?",
              "Answer": "North Star"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following played a vital role in helping fugitive slaves escape to the North?",
              "Answer": "Underground Railroad"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Of the states listed, which one was the most affected by the Second Great Awakening?",
              "Answer": "New York"
            },
            {
              "Question": "During the Second Great Awakening, the Methodists, the Baptists, and the Presbyterians were associated with __________.",
              "Answer": "evangelical Protestantism"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following did the preachers who participated in the Second Great Awakening appeal to the most?",
              "Answer": "emotion"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 13":[
            {
              "Question": "In the nineteenth century, the United States acquired most of what is now the Southwest from which country?",
              "Answer": "Mexico"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the spirit of Young America?",
              "Answer": "Manifest Destiny"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would a Young American most likely support?",
              "Answer": "market economy"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the 1820s, the Mexican government's requirement that Anglo-American settlers in Texas __________ generated popular resistance.",
              "Answer": "emancipate their slaves"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who was the first president of Texas?",
              "Answer": "Sam Houston"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Those who opposed the immediate annexation of Texas warned that such a move would trigger a war with which country?",
              "Answer": "Mexico"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following came under U.S. control as a result of the Mexican-American War?",
              "Answer": "California"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following highlights the link between slavery and the Mexican-American War?",
              "Answer": "Wilmot Proviso"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The expansion of railroads contributed to the development of a domestic __________ industry.",
              "Answer": "iron"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following correctly matches the person to his invention?",
              "Answer": "Elias Howe - sewing machine"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The majority of immigrants who came to the United States in the middle of the nineteenth century were from __________.",
              "Answer": "Ireland"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to Irish workers, the new working class of former farmers was more likely to __________.",
              "Answer": "resist factory discipline"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to earlier artisans and craftsmen, the new class of industrial workers that emerged during the 1840s and 1850s __________.",
              "Answer": "was less skilled"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The territory gained from the Mexican-American War is located primarily in which area of the United States?",
              "Answer": "southwest"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was an immediate cause of the Mexican-American War?",
              "Answer": "a border dispute between Texas and Mexico"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Texas became a U.S. territory during which president's administration?",
              "Answer": "John Tyler"
            }
          ],
        "Chapter 14":[
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people was a Republican?",
              "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Northerners associated \"bully Brooks\" with __________.",
              "Answer": "slavery"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following stirred sectional antagonism in the middle of the nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "Kansas-Nebraska Act"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Constitution explicitly give the federal government authority to do on the issue of slavery?",
              "Answer": "abolish the international slave trade"
            },
            {
              "Question": "As a result of the Compromise of 1850, what did the North gain?",
              "Answer": "admission of California as a free state"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people would have been the most likely to oppose the Wilmot Proviso?",
              "Answer": "southerners"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was included in the Compromise of 1850 to appease the South?",
              "Answer": "passage of a new fugitive slave law"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What allowed settlers of a territory to vote for or against slavery at the first meeting of a territorial legislature?",
              "Answer": "popular sovereignty"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the middle of the nineteenth century, most Whigs were __________.",
              "Answer": "evangelical Protestants"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was a consequence of the Kansas-Nebraska Act?",
              "Answer": "repeal of the Missouri Compromise"
            },
            {
              "Question": "John Brown took part in which of the following?",
              "Answer": "Pottawatomie Massacre"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the Ostend Manifesto, the Pierce administration expressed its goal to acquire __________.",
              "Answer": "Cuba"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the influence of nativism on American politics today?",
              "Answer": "Donald Trump's campaign promises"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people would agree with the portrayal of slavery presented in Harriet Beecher Stowe's Uncle Tom's Cabin?",
              "Answer": "Herman Melville"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The debate between __________ in 1858 became a forum for the debate over slavery in the territories.",
              "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln and Stephen Douglas"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was part of the Republican platform in the election of 1860?",
              "Answer": "federal funding for a transcontinental railroad"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which party won the presidential election of 1860?",
              "Answer": "Republican"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects a common ground between the North and the South in the middle of the nineteenth century?",
              "Answer": "commitment to republican ideals"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who clubbed Senator Charles Sumner with a cane in response to the controversy over Bleeding Kansas?",
              "Answer": "Preston Brooks"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following set the Mason-Dixon line as the division between free and slave states in western territories?",
              "Answer": "Missouri Compromise"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects a defeat for the abolitionist movement?",
              "Answer": "the Dred Scott decision"
            }
          ],
          "Chapter 15":[
            {
              "Question": "Abraham Lincoln was elected president in which year?",
              "Answer": 1860
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people called for the end of slavery's expansion westward?",
              "Answer": "Abraham Lincoln"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would Abraham Lincoln most likely support?",
              "Answer": "extension of citizenship to African Americans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which group believed that the slave states should act as a unit on the secession issue?",
              "Answer": "cooperationists"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Why did Virginia, North Carolina, Tennessee, and Arkansas resist calls for immediate secession from the Union?",
              "Answer": "Their economies were more strongly tied to the North."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects the constitutional theory behind the secession from the Union?",
              "Answer": "The Union was a compact of sovereign states, each of which had the right to leave it."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following slave states remained loyal to the Union?",
              "Answer": "Kentucky"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following produced or procured sufficient armaments to keep southern armies well supplied throughout the Civil War?",
              "Answer": "Confederate Ordnance Bureau"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects Abraham Lincoln's exercise of executive power during the Civil War?",
              "Answer": "suspension of the writ of habeas corpus"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Supreme Court during both the Lincoln and Bush administrations held that presidents did not have the authority to __________.",
              "Answer": "create military tribunals"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Union occupation of __________ paved the way for a blockade of the southern coast.",
              "Answer": "New Orleans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who took command of the Confederate Army?",
              "Answer": "Robert E. Lee"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Abraham Lincoln issued his preliminary Emancipation Proclamation after the battle at __________.",
              "Answer": "Antietam"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following earned Abraham Lincoln the title of the Great Emancipator?",
              "Answer": "the Thirteenth Amendment"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Enrollment Act of 1863 provided the basis for __________.",
              "Answer": "conscription"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What were the militant advocates of \"peace at any price\" called?",
              "Answer": "Copperheads"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In contrast to Abraham Lincoln, George McClellan, the Democratic candidate in the 1864 election, __________.",
              "Answer": "did not insist on emancipation"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Who controlled Congress during the Civil War?",
              "Answer": "Republicans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "During the Civil War, northern women played an important role in which of the following?",
              "Answer": "During the Civil War, northern women played an important role in which of the following?"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following principles was affirmed by the Union victory in the Civil War?",
              "Answer": "supremacy of the federal government over the states"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which state had the highest number of free African Americans in 1860?",
              "Answer": "Virginia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What was the first major confrontation between the Union and the Confederacy in the Civil War?",
              "Answer": "Bull Run"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Civil War motivate Britain to do?",
              "Answer": "occupy Egypt"
            }
          ],
          "Chapter 16": [
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following people was a southern Democrat?",
              "Answer": "Andrew Johnson"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did Robert Smalls have in common with Radical Republicans?",
              "Answer": "They supported full citizenship rights for black male citizens."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following would Robert Smalls have supported?",
              "Answer": "free and compulsory public education"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflected the goals of Abraham Lincoln's Proclamation of Amnesty and Reconstruction?",
              "Answer": "Ten Percent Plan"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following indicates that Andrew Johnson favored a minimal Reconstruction policy?",
              "Answer": "his generosity in granting pardons to the Confederate elite"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which amendment is often invoked today in cases concerning affirmative action and reproductive choice?",
              "Answer": "Fourteenth Amendment"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the first Reconstruction Act passed by Congress in 1867 do?",
              "Answer": "divided the South into five military districts"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which president faced charges of impeachment?",
              "Answer": "Andrew Johnson"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following best describes the differences in the ideas about freedom held by former slaves and their northern allies?",
              "Answer": "Former slaves attempted to maintain the family task system of work rather than adopt the individual piecework system northern capitalists pushed."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Most northerners and southerners assumed that southern prosperity after the Civil War would depend on __________.",
              "Answer": "cotton production"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What term refers to former Whig planters and merchants in the South who hoped to realize their dreams in industry and commerce?",
              "Answer": "scalawags"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Credit Mobilier scandal occurred during whose presidency?",
              "Answer": "Ulysses S. Grant"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following reflects a way that former slaves in the South asserted their freedom after the Civil War ended?",
              "Answer": "establishing the African Methodist Episcopal Church"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Under the Fifteenth Amendment, which of the following could no longer be used to limit the suffrage?",
              "Answer": "prior status as a slave"
            },
            {
              "Question": "How did Elizabeth Cady Stanton and Susan B. Anthony react to the Fifteenth Amendment?",
              "Answer": "They campaigned against its ratification."
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following was associated with the Ku Klux Klan?",
              "Answer": "Knights of the White Camellia"
            },
            {
              "Question": "During Reconstruction, which group would have been the most sympathetic to the Ku Klux Klan?",
              "Answer": "conservative Democrats"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The election of __________ as president marked the end of Reconstruction.",
              "Answer": "Rutherford B. Hayes"
            },
            {
              "Question": "In the 1876 election, the results from which states were contested?",
              "Answer": "South Carolina, Florida, and Louisiana"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The Redeemers shared a commitment to __________.",
              "Answer": "laissez-faire economics"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did the Ku Klux Klan and the Redeemers share in common?",
              "Answer": "belief in white supremacy"
            },
            {
              "Question": "The states with the highest percentage of the population unable to write who were African American were concentrated in which part of the United States?",
              "Answer": "southeastern"
            },
            {
              "Question": "What did Radical Republicans regard as a key goal of Reconstruction?",
              "Answer": "extending political rights to African Americans"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Which of the following groups would be most opposed to Reconstruction?",
              "Answer": "southern Democrats"
            },
            {
              "Question": "Should the Fourteenth Amendment be interpreted according to the intent of the people who ratified it during Reconstruction, or should our understanding of it evolve as times change? For example, should the right to equal protection under the law include marrying a person of any race or gender? Explain.",
              "Answer": "Shared Writing"
            }
          ]

    }
}